Previously on "Vikings":
마침내, 다시한번 서쪽으로 갈때가 왔습니다.
Ragnar: We shall finally go west again.
호릭왕과 보르그 족장이 우리와 함께할 것입니다.
King Horik and Jarl Borg shall join us.
신부님 안녕?
Hello, priest.
_
영국이 그리웠나?
Ragnar: Do you ever miss England?
- 가끔은.
- 그럼 같이 가자.
- Athelstan: Sometimes.
Ragnar: Come with me.
우린 별의별 신들의 도움이 다 필요하거든,
We will need the help of all the gods,
너네 신도 포함해서 말이야.
including yours.
동생한테 가서 이야기좀 해봐요.
(롤로는 라그나동생이 아니라 형이예요!!)
Siggy: Go and speak with your brother.
다시한번 존중받을 기회를 줘.
I ask only for the opportunity
to regain your respect.
내가 왜 너를 다시 믿어야 되지?
Why should I ever trust you again?
이렇게 예언하죠.
뱀모양이 그려진
Aslaug: I make this prophecy:
Your son will be born
아이가 태어날 꺼예요.
with the image of the serpent in his eye.
보르그 족장과는 같이 가고 싶지 않네.
I do not wish Jarl Borg to raid with us.
조약으로 맺어진것 아닌가?
I thought we had an agreement?
착하신 동생을 버려.
Jarl Borg: Abandon your brother for good.
으악
Oh! (Grunts in pain)
북쪽인들이 웨섹스에 상륙했습니다.
Messenger: The Northmen
have come ashore in Wessex.
그리고 우리의 군대를 물리쳤습니다.
They've defeated a large force of our men.
_
에츄베르트왕? 들어본적 있나?
What have you heard about King Ecbert?
딱 자네 같다고 들었지.
That he's just like you.
♪
♪ More, give me more ♪
♪ give me more ♪
♪ if I had a heart I could love you ♪
♪ if I had a voice I would sing ♪
♪ after the night when I wake up ♪
♪ I'll see what tomorrow brings ♪
♪ I... I... I... ♪
♪ If I had a voice I would sing ♪
- 기미갤 Chickholic자막
배포자유, 번역오류는 rhoads83@naver.com
으로 보내주시면 수정하겠습니다 -
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -
- (Birds chirping)
- _
(Foliage crunching
underfoot, morning doves cry)
저긴 뭐하는데지?
Ragnar: What is that place?
기독교 교회야, 대사원이라고
Athelstan: It's a
Christian church, a minster.
그중에서 좀 큰거지.
아마 여긴 윈체스터 겠네.
A large one. It may be Winchester.
중요한덴가?
Is it important?
윈체스터라면 성 비리노가 뭍인곳이지.
If it is Winchester, Saint
Birinus is buried there.
굉장한 성지야.
It's a place of great pilgrimage.
보물이 있을까?
And will there be treasure there?
그럼, 아주 많을껄.
(Chortles) Yes. A lot of treasure.
흠!
Floki: (Happy) Hmm!
(Grasses crunch underfoot)
북부인들이 웨섹스에 온건
King Ecbert: There's no surprise to me
딱히 놀랄일도 아니야.
that these Northmen have arrived in Wessex.
노섬브리아가 습격당했단 이야기를
들었을때,
After I heard about their
raids into Northumbria,
그 놈들이 이리로 오는건
I realized it was only a matter of time
시간문제라고 봤거든.
before they came ashore here.
내가 샤를마뉴황제 밑에 있을때,
When I lived at the court
of the Emperor Charlemagne,
북부인들은 이미 제국을 공격해서
these Northmen had already
emerged from their lairs
소굴을 늘려가고 있었거든
to attack parts of his empire.
남부갈리아에 있는
항구마을에서열린
I was with Charlemagne's
party at a harbor town
샤를마뉴 황제의 파티였지
in Southern Gaul.
저녁먹을 때쯤에
And as we sat eating supper
해적함대가 항구를 공격했어
a fleet of pirates attacked the harbor.
처음엔 어떤놈들인지 몰랐지만
There was some confusion
about their identity,
배 모양이라던가
but from the build of their ships
물살을 가르는 속도를 보고,
and their speed through the water,
황제는 북부인들인것을 알아챘어.
the Emperor recognized
them at once as Northmen.
번개같이 공격하고....
After a lightning attack...
(Sharp exhale)
내빼버렸지....
They made their escape.
황제는 부하들에게 추격을 명령했지만
The Emperor's men took up the chase,
순식간에 배타고 사라졌어.
but they were soon out-sailed.
이젠 내가 이 깡패이자 이교도놈들을
처리할때가 온거로구만
And now it is our turn to
deal with these ruffians,
these pagans.
놈들을 처리해야되..
But deal with them we shall...
반드시.
And must.
애설울프?
Aethelwulf?
네, 아버님.
Yes, Father.
너에게 가신들과 함께
King Ecbert: I put it in your hands
군대를 양성할 것을 맡기겠다.
to work with our
Ealdormen to raise an army.
그와중에 스파이를 보내서
In the meantime, we shall
send spies and others
그놈들의 규모를 파악하고
to observe the size of the raiding party,
목적이 무었인지 확인해 보도록.
and their intentions.
북부인들은 배에서 멀리떨어지는
모험을 좋아할리 없어
These Northmen never like to
venture far from their ships
그리고 가급적 전투는
피하고 싶어할꺼야.
and they prefer not to be
drawn into pitched battle.
겁내지 말되, 조심하도록
Let us not be afraid, but rather watchful.
(Retreating footsteps)
(Bird cries out)
라그리타
Sigvard: Lagertha!
(Sheep bleat)
왜 내가 당신을 쫓아다녀야 되지?
Why must I follow you up the fields?
넌 내 마누라라고.
You're my wife.
우린 붙어있어야 하는건 당연한거고
You should be at my side,
중요한 손님이 있을땐 더더욱 그렇다고
especially when we have important guests.
난 내 아들이 모욕당하는꼴을
보고 있기 싫습니다.
I will not stay to hear my son insulted.
네 아들은 자기 분수를 알아야되.
Sigvard: Your son should know his place.
그 놈은 계속 반항적으로 군다고
He continues to be resentful.
내가 얼마나 사랑하고
있는지도 모르고말이야.
He refuses to accept or
acknowledge my love for him.
당신은 내 아들을 사랑하지 않아요.
Lagertha: You don't love my son.
어느 누구도 사랑하지 않죠, 시그바르드.
You don't love anyone, Sigvard.
어떻게 하는지도 모르죠.
You don't know how to.
악!
(Hard slap) Aghhh!
용서하게 라그리타,
난 자제력이 없는 남자야.
Sigvard: Forgive me, Lagertha.
I'm an intemperate man.
자신을 통제하는게 어려운거 알어.
I find it difficult to control myself.
하지만 내 방식대로 당신을 사랑하고 원해
But I have loved and
desired you after my fashion
그리고 당신 아들과 뭔가 타협점을 찾는다면
and if your son will only meet me halfway,
그녀석의 장래도 보장해 줄 수있지.
I will make sure he has a good future.
(Foliage rustles in the wind, birds chirp)
(Foliage rustles underfoot)
(Birds chirping)
(Unsheathes sword)
(Townsfolk chatter, sheep bleat)
(Panicked gasps)
(Bell clangs)
비상!! 북부인들이 온다!!
Soldier 1: The alarm! Northmen coming!
보이나?
Soldier 2: Do you see them?
- 빨리!
- 안으로!! 어서!!
- Soldier 1: Quickly!
- Soldier 2: Inside, now!
- Soldier 3: Altogether!
- Soldier 4: Gab inne!
(Panicked yelling and screaming)
- Soldier 5: Inside! Gab inne!
- (Unsheathes sword)
(Panicked chatter)
으앗!
Ungh! Oof!
- Monk: Come!
- Man 1: Stay together!
- Soldier 1: 준비됐나?!
- Soldier 2: 발검!
- Soldier 1: Are you ready?!
- Soldier 2: Weapons!
(Doors thud shut)
물건을 챙겨.
Man: The stuff is packed.
(Bell clangs)
(Sheep bleat)
(Foliage rustles underfoot)
(Bleating)
Saxons: (Attack screams fill the air)
Vikings: (Battle cries)
(Weapons clank, fighting grunts)
(Throwing grunt)
(Sword slices) Ughhh!
(Weapons clank, fighting grunts)
으아! 억!
Agh! Ugh!
으아아아아!!
Athelstan: Aggghhhhh!
으아!
Ungh! Oof!
(Weapons clank, fighting grunts)
(Sword slices, screams of pain)
(Fighting grunts)
(Weapons clank, fighting grunts)
Aggghhhhhhhh!
Soldier: (Frightened yelps)
앗!!
(Sword stabs) Agh!
(Fighting grunts)
으아아아아!
Agghhhhh!
억! 억!
(Arrow whooshes) Ungh! Agh!
앗!
(Arrow whooshes) Agghhh!
악!
(Horse whinnies) Ungh!
(Shields clack, weapons
clank as they regroup)
(Warriors converse quietly)
(Sheep bleat)
(Quiets down)
함정일지 몰라!
Torstein: Could be a trap!
쉴드월!
Shield-wall!
(Shields clatter into place)
(Doors creak open)
(Geese honk in alarm, rooster crows)
열어.
Open.
(Shields clatter)
(Footsteps scuff)
어디로 가버렸지?
King Horik: Where have they all gone?
보물이 있어야되는데.
Floki: There should be treasure.
얘가 보물이 있을꺼랬어.
He said there would be treasure.
왜 항상 얘말을 듣지?
Why do you always listen to him?
어디있어?
Where is it?
저기.
Athelstan: It's over there.
이거? 이건 보물이 아니야!
King Horik: This?! This is not treasure!
빈 나무 태이블일 뿐이라고.
This is an empty wooden table.
아닙니다, 호릭님(King Horic인데
단순하게 가겠습니다).
You are mistaken, King Horik.
지금 서계신
여기가 보물이예요 .
The treasure is here.
You're standing on it.
(Knocks twice)
뭐?
Vikings: (Confused murmurs) What?
(Grunts of effort)
(Floorboards crack, shouts of excitement)
그렇군!!!
Horik: (Laughs delightedly) You were right!
(Laughing, coins clink)
보물이다!
Treasure!
(Warriors grunt, chest thuds heavily)
어떻게 알았지?
Ragnar: How did you know?
기독교인들의 습관이야.
Athelstan: It is a Christian habit
위인들의 뼈를 제단아래 뭍거든.
to bury the bones of the
revered dead beneath the alter.
라그나!
Ragnar!
(Warriors laugh and chatter excitedly)
나도 좀 보자
King Horik: Let me see that!
(Warriors laugh excitedly, objects clatter)
이건 누구야?
Ragnar: Who was this?
아마 성 비리노일꺼야.
Athelstan: It must be Saint Birinus.
King Horik: Here! There's more!
성(Saint)가 뭔지 알려줘봐
Ragnar: You keep talking to
me like I know what a Saint is.
성은.. 특히 성스러운 삶을 살고,
Athelstan: A Saint is a man who
has lived a particularly holy life,
기적을 보였거나,
performed some miracle,
신념에의해 죽을 뭐 그런사람들이야.
or been martyred killed for their beliefs.
호릭왕: 금이다
King Horik: It's all gold!
근데 죽으면 무슨 소용이야?
But I am dead. What use can I be?
(Chuckles)
기독교인들은 그 뼈들이
Christians believe that the bones
여전히 축복해준다고 믿어.
can still exert benediction.
기적을 일으킨다거나.
Can perform miracles.
기적은 또 뭐야?
What is a miracle?
일어날 수 없는 일이랄까?
Miracles are things...
which are impossible to do.
King Horik: Take it all!
Warrior 1: It's heavy!
잠깐!
Torstein: Wait!
(Scuffing dirt away)
(Trapdoor creaks open,
villagers gasp in fear)
Man: What do they want?
Women: (Scream in fear)
(Hand brushes against paper)
(Axe thuds lightly)
(Stifled panicked breaths)
(Ink pot rattles)
안되 멈춰!
Monk: No! Stop!
으앗!
(Axe strikes) Ungh!
(Gasps for breath)
(Gasps weakly, slumps heavily)
(Approaching footsteps)
주여 저들을 용서하소서..
Bishop Swithern: (In Anglo
Saxon) Dear Lord, forgive them,
그들이 하는일을 스스로 알게 하소서
for they know not what they do.
숨어!
_
어떻게 우리말을 알지?
Bishop Swithern: You
speak our language?! How?
그딴게 중요한게 아니야 숨으라고!
It doesn't matter. Just do as I say. Hide!
- 숨지않으면 죽는다고!
- 동포로군!
- Hide or they will kill you.
- You are one of us!
한때는.
Once.
그럼 이리말하지
Bishop Swithern: Then I will tell you this:
언젠가 넌 잡힐꺼야.
One day, you will be caught.
넌 잡혀서 심자가에 못박힐꺼다.
We will catch you and crucify you...
신에 눈에 가장 더럽고 혐오스러운
변절자로
for an apostate is the lowest
and the vilest of all creatures
낙인찍히게 될 것이다.
in the eyes of God!
오!
Floki: Oh!
- 데려가봐야 겠군!
(Speaking Old Norse)
(Women scream in terror, warriors laugh)
(Treasure clatters, women scream in terror)
좀 높은 신부인가봐
(Speaking Old Norse)
우리 신한테 설교해봐.
King Horik: (Speaking Old Norse)
신은 하나밖에 없다며?
내가보기엔 넌 그냥 늙은 바보 거짓말쟁이야.
_
신들은 널 싫어하지.. 근데 난 더 싫어해.
Bishop Swithern: Salve,
nobilis, et pretiose...
얍!
(Hard punch) Ungh!
Floki and Vikings: (Laughing)
묶어! 같이좀 놀아주자!
(Speaking Old Norse)
Warriors: (Cheering)
(Bishop grunts)
(Warriors chatter excitedly)
어쩔샘이야?
Athelstan: What will happen to him?
기다려보면 알겠지?!
Floki: You just wait and see, priest!
(Laughter)
(Cheering) Warrior: Woo-hoo!
주여....
Bishop Swithern: (Prays in Latin) Domine...
(Arrow whooshes, bishop
groans, Vikings cheer)
Rescipe ergo in me oculis
misercordiae tuae...
(Objects clatter)
(Door creaks open)
(Celebratory cheering)
Warrior: (Shouting in Old Norse)
(Grains scatter)
Warrior 2: Give it to me!
Warrior 3: (In Old Norse) Treasure!
여기봐!
Here!
Warrior 4: (In Old Norse) 이것보라구!
Warrior 4: (In Old Norse) Look! Look!
(Raucous laughter)
(Objects clatter, warriors chatter)
- Warrior 1: Help me!
- Warrior 2: Here!
(Objects clatter)
(Arrow whooshes, bishop groans in pain)
Vikings: (Cheering) Woo!
(Boisterous laughter)
Bishop Swithern: (Weakly)
Domini, creatura tue,
qua tuo sanguine redemisti...
- 죽이면 안되 플로키
- Warrior: Don't kill him, Floki.
- Bishop Swithern: Penitent...
윽!
(Arrow whooshes) Ungh!
Vikings: (Cheer loudly)
Bishop Swithern: Penitent me.
아직도 이야기를해? 늙은 염소가 터프하네.
Floki: Is he still talking? Tough old goat.
엘렌두르 조용히 시켜, 주둥이를 맞춰버려.
King Horik: Erlendur, quiet
him. Right in his mouth.
- 뭐야?
- 저리 비켜.
- Warrior: What's he doing?
- Warrior 2: Out of the way.
(Axe clatters)
Bishop Swithern: (Weak, mumbled praying)
(Inhales sharply)
Deus tippi benidicas.
고통없이 구원받으시길.
Suffer no more, but trust in thy salvation.
(Bishop gasps, blade scrapes)
(Sighs)
(Boisterous chatter resumes)
(Knife clinks)
(Chatter and laughter fills great hall)
어머니 왜 어머니한테 그따위로하게
놔두는 거예요?
Bjorn: Mother, why would you
allow him to do that to you?
무슨말이니?
What are you talking about?
당신남편 시그바르드 백작, 아까 봤어요!
Your husband, Earl Sigvard,
I saw him!
비욘, 제발.
(Warningly) Bjorn, please.
제발 뭐요?
Please what?
전에도 때렸나요?
Has he hit you before?
다시 때리게 놔둘꺼예요?
Will you let him hit you again?
다신 그런일 없을꺼야.
It will never happen again.
만약 그런다면 난 저놈을 죽일꺼예요.
If it does, I'll kill him.
그런일 없을꺼라고.
I said it won't.
라그나가 뭐라고 할까요?
What would Ragnar say?
이게 니 아빠랑 무슨 상관인데?
What has it to do with your father?
아무것도 아니야!
Nothing!
가끔 아빠 생각을해요.
Sometimes I think of him.
그리운데, 어쩔수 없네요.
I miss him. I can't help it.
Sigvard: Skol! (Laughing)
당연하지. 넌 니아빠 아들이니깐.
Of course not. You're his son.
자긍심을 가지거라.
You must always be proud.
엄마도 아빠의 아내로 있었어야 했어요!
As should you for being his wife!
Sigvard and men: (Laugh and chatter)
(Laughter, low hum of chatter)
(Sighs heavily)
(Townsfolk chatter,
children shout playfully)
(Sheep bleat)
(Hurried footsteps)
(Exhales)
(Water splashes)
(Baby coos softly)
또 아들이예요?
Siggy: Another son?
네.
Aslaug: Yes.
이름이 뭐죠?
What is his name?
시구르드, 우리 아버지에게서 땄어요.
Sigurd, after my father.
(Sigurd coos softly)
뱀을 눈에 품은 시구르드.
Sigurd snake-in-the-eye.
Soldier: (Shouts) Guard the gate!
페하
Lord Eadric: Your Majesty,
윈체스터가 공격당한것 아십니까?
you have heard of the attack on Winchester?
물론.
Of course.
슬픈 일이지.
I grieve.
내 부하주교가 순교했습니다,
Bishop Edmund: The martyrdom
of my fellow bishop,
스위든 주교요, 훌륭한 기독교인이죠.
Bishop Swithern, a fine Christian.
신계 기도하지.
King Ecbert: Praise be to God.
매우 중요한 곳이니만큼
Lord Eadric: There are those
who ask why we did not do more
우리 형제자매들을 지키기 위해서
to protect our brothers and sisters
더 주의를 기울여야 한다고
말씀드렸지요.
at such an important site.
그런가?
Are there?
내 왕국은 매우커.
My kingdom is very large.
중요한 곳은 많고.
There are many important sites.
전부 지킬 수 있을까? 아니야.
Could I protect all of them? No.
그 이교도들을
발견하기를 바라지 않았던가?
Did I want to discover where
the pagans would strike?
그랬지.
Yes.
그리고 그놈들이 어디있는지를 알게되었지.
For now I know where they are.
그럼....
Bishop Edmund: So...
스위든 주교는 헛되지 않은 희생을 했군요.
Bishop Swithern was a necessary sacrifice.
신의 백성으로요,
As a man of God,
그는 기꺼이 순교할 기회를
받아들였을꺼야.
I assumed he welcomed the
opportunity for martyrdom.
그렇지 않은가?
Or do you disagree?
그럼요
Bishop Edmund: Oh no, sire.
모든 성직자들은 자신의 운명에 의해
All of the cloth would welcome martyrdom
순교하여 주예수그리스도에게
in the cause of our faith,
봉사할 수 있기를 바라마지않죠.
service of our Lord Jesus Christ.
좋아.
Good.
그러한 귀중한 기회를
Because I'm going to offer you
마련해주도록 하지
precisely that same opportunity,
대주교,
my Lord Bishop,
아마 금방일꺼야.
and, I trust, very soon.
(Nervous sigh)
Lord Eadric: (Sighs heavily)
(Water churns and splashes)
(Hammering)
Warrior: Look at these, nice and strong.
Tight enough?
널 위해 뭔가를 준비했어 에설스턴
I have something for you, Athelstan.
이거 필요없어?
Don't you want it?
이런게 신을 떠올리게 하나?
Are these not the images of your God?
또 말하게 하는군
I told you before, and
I will tell you again:
내 신은 오딘이야, 모두의 아버지.
My God is Odin, the all father.
니가 그말 한거 알어.
I know you told me.
그냥.. 믿지 못하겠는거야.
Only... I don't believe you.
이거 보여? 라그나가 줬어.
And this? Ragnar gave me this.
개목걸이 했다고 개가 되는건 아니지.
Wearing a dog-turd doesn't make you a dog.
오.
Oh.
또 줄게 있어.
I have something else for you.
성자님의 손이지, 그치.
The hand of your holy man, I believe.
(Giggles)
그러니깐
Ragnar: So tell me,
어떻게 잉글랜드를 발견했죠?
how do you find England?
부와 즐거움의 땅이지.
Horik: It is a pleasant
land, rich with treasure.
맞아요, 여긴 부유하죠.
You are right. This land is rich.
하지만, 이게 진짜 보물이죠!
But here... here is the real treasure!
(Inhales deeply)
흙? 이런게 뭐?
Earth? Have you not seen?
가는데 마다 경작하고 있어요.
Everywhere we go, there are crops.
식량이 자라는거예요.
There is food growing.
나도 내 아버지도 농부예요,
I am a farmer and the son of a farmer,
이게 내가 이해하는거예요.
and this is what I understand.
가난한 우리 나라랑 비교해봐요
농사짓기도 힘들고,
Compared to our poor countries,
where it is hard to farm,
살기도 힘들고..
hard to live.
근데 여긴 쉬워요.
Here, it is easy.
우리가 여기 살면 모두를 먹여살릴수 있어요.
If we lived here, we could feed everybody.
굶주릴 것도 없구요.
There would be no hunger.
좋은 생각이야
하지만 질문이 있어:
I like your thinking,
but here is my question:
색슨족이 곱게 우리랑 같이 살도록
Will the Saxons simply invite us
초대해줄까? 응?
to live among them, hmm?
(Loud cheering and applause)
(Music and applause fill the great hall)
- Man: Jarl Borg!
- Man 2: To your new bride!
(Applause)
Man 3: A fine choice this day!
Jarl Borg: Thank you!
(Loud cheering and applause)
Man 4: A fine choice, my lord!
(Excited buzz of chatter and applause)
(Quiets down)
두번째로 결혼하게 되었군요.
So I am married for the second time.
아시다 시피,
As most of you know,
내 첫번째 결혼은 한시간도 못갔죠,
my first marriage lasted less than an hour,
내 형이 술에 독을 탔거든요.
because my own brother
poisoned the drinks that day.
그런일은 당연히 없어야죠
Of course, the same thing
can never happen twice,
자, 와인 퍼마십시다.
so let the wine be poured.
Men and women: (Cheering) Yeah! Here, here!
(Applause, cheering, banging on tables)
자, 누가 처음으로 축배를 들까요?
Now who will be the first
to drink in celebration?
저요.
I will.
아니야, 아니야, 두번은 싫어.
No! No, I could not bear
it. Not a second time.
제가 먹어 보죠.
Let me taste the wine.
(Gulping)
(Uneasy silence)
괜찮은거 같네요.
It's quite all right.
Skol!
(Applause, cheering, banging on tables)
중요하게 드릴 말씀이 또 있습니다.
Jarl Borg: I have something
else important to say.
좋은날을 망치고 싶진 않지만
I don't wish to dampen the celebrations
여러분 모두 저와
but you all know that the
agreement between myself,
호릭왕 그리고 라그나 사이에 맺은
협약이 깨졌단 말씀을 드려야 겠네요.
King Horik, and Ragnar
Lothbrok has been broken.
그들은 나와 여러분들을 빼고
습격을 갔어요.
They have gone raiding
west without me, without us,
이건 나를 모욕하는것 뿐만 아니라
which is an insult not only to myself,
여러분 모를 모욕하는 거예요.
but to all of you,
내 부인과
and now also to my wife,
부인의 가족까지도요
and to my wife's family.
(Murmurs of agreement)
이런 모욕을 두고볼수가 없군요.
I have to do something about this insult.
뭐, 호릭왕을 비방좀 하자면
Frankly, I blame King Horik
more for what has happened,
더불어서,
but at the same time,
라그나 백작의 땅에 벌어지는 일좀
포함해서요.
consider what is happening
to Earl Ragnar's lands.
그는 마누라와 주정뱅이 형을
He has abandoned them
살피기를 포기했어요.
to the care of his wife
and his drunken brother.
(Laughter)
나와 내 가족을 모욕한 이를
In order to punish those
벌하기 위해서,
who have insulted me and my family,
라그나 로그브록에 대한 복수를
I declare today that I will seek vengeance
선포합니다.
against Ragnar Lothbrok.
모든신들에 의해,
By all our gods,
난 놈의 모든 땅을 점령하고
I swear that we will seize all his lands
그형놈의 배반을 내 도끼로
and that I will repay
his brother's treachery
되갚아 줄것을 맹세합니다.
with the axe.
All: (Cheer in agreement)
(Birds chirping)
(Foliage rustles underfoot)
(Hooves plod, horses snort softly)
(Horses snort and whinny)
우리말 할수 있는 사람 있나?
Bishop Edmund: Who can speak to us?
나.
I can.
난 웨섹스의 왕이신 에츄베르트왕의 사자로,
I have been sent here by Ecbert,
이곳에 왔네
King of Wessex.
왕께선 윈체스터의 교회를
The king regrets your attack
공격한것을 유감스럽게 생각하시네.
on the holy church at Winchester.
그리고 그 이상으로 그분의 왕국에
He wonders how much longer
너희들이 얼마나 있다갈 것인가 궁금해 하시네.
you intend to remain in his kingdom?
(Nervously clears throat)
뭐, 이런건 말이죠
Ragnar: Well, that depends.
이런건?
Bishop Edmund: Upon what?
그분께서 가라 하시거나
Ragnar: Upon what he'll
offer us to leave...
머물라 하시라느냐에 달린문제죠.
or what he'll offer us to stay.
머문다고?
Stay?
그럼요, 우리는 왕이랑
사이좋게 지내고 싶다구요.
Ragnar: Yes, we want to
make peace with the king.
평화롭게?
Peace.
(Tries to clear throat)
그럼 당신네들은 더이상 안죽여도 되구요.
So we don't have to kill any more of you.
왕에게 메세지를 전하지.
I will relay your message to the king.
(Floki giggles)
(Claps twice)
잠깐!
King Horik: (In Old Norse) Wait!
(Hard slash) Ughhh!
(Giggles)
(Slashing blows, grunts of effort)
Bishop Edmund: (Struggling grunts)
Vikings: (Laughing)
Floki: (Giggles)
Bishop Edmund: (Collapses) Agh!
Vikings: (Laughing)
(Horse whinnies, hooves thunder)
배안고프니 비욘?
Sigvard: Not hungry, Bjorn?
안고파요.
No.
왜?
Sigvard: Any reason?
그냥요.
No reason.
불행하니?
Sigvard: Are you unhappy?
어떻게하면 니가 행복할까.
What can I do to make you happy?
대충 아무대나 처들어가서
Shall I raid one of my
unsuspecting neighbours,
넌 싸움실력좀 보여주거나
so you can show off your fighting skills,
뭐 다죽여 버리거나?
and maybe slaughter them all?
니가 진정한 라그나 로스브록의
아들임을 보이는거지!
Show that you are truly
the son of Ragnar Lothbrok?!
Sigvard and men: (Laugh)
아니야,
Sigvard: No, believe me,
난 니가 침통해 하는걸 보고 싶지 않아.
I do not like to see you so solemn.
그러니 말해보렴 어떻게 해줄까?
So tell me, what can I do?
산에 있는 오두막에 살게 해주실수 있죠.
Bjorn: You can let me go live
in a cabin in the mountains.
혼자서? 산중에?
Sigvard: By yourself? In the mountains?
네, 스스로를 시험해보고 싶어요.
Bjorn: Yes. I'd like to test myself.
모든것에서 떨어져가지구요. 하인들
Get away from all this. All these servants!
우릴 위해 모든걸 해주는 사람들...
All these people doing everything for us.
삶에 꼭 필요한게 뭔지 알고 싶어요.
I want to know what is essential to life.
가장 중요한게 무엇인지요.
What is really important.
보내주시겠어요?
Will you let me?
안되, 당연히 안되지.
No, of course not.
난 여기 백작이야.
I am the Earl here.
의붓아들이 산에있는 되지우리 같은데서
굶거나 얼어죽기라도 하면
What would folk think if
I let my beloved stepson
사람들이 어떻게 생각하겠니?
starve or freeze to death
in some mountain pigsty?
Sigvard and men: (Laugh)
이해해줄수 있겠지? 얘야?
Sigvard: You understand
that, don't you, my boy?
어떤 경우에도,
In any case,
라그리타에게 맹새컨데
I have solemnly sworn to Lagertha
난 너를 책임질거다. 그렇고 말고
that I shall take care of you, and I will.
(Fire crackles in the silence)
(Waterfall gushes)
(Waves lap at the shore)
(Water churns)
롤로
Siggy: Rollo! (Sighs)
롤로 일어나요
Siggy: Rollo, wake up!
뭐, 뭐야..
Rollo: (Exasperated) What? What is it?
배들이 오고있어요.
- Siggy: There are boats!
- Rollo: (Sighs)
누구죠?
Siggy: Who are they?
누군지 알거 같군
Rollo: I think I can guess.
마을로 돌아가.
Go back to the town.
누구든 무기를 들고 싸울수
있는 사람들을 모아봐.
Find anyone who can fight,
anyone who can hold a weapon.
적습이야.
We're under attack.
(Water churns)
롤로, 무슨일이예요, 어떻게 된거예요?
Aslaug: Rollo, what is
it? What is happening?
보르그 족장이야. 우릴 공격하러 오고있어.
Rollo: Jarl Borg! He has
come back to attack us.
보르그?
Aslaug: Jarl Borg?
확실해, 그야
Rollo: (Panting) I'm sure it is him.
라그나와 호릭이 그와의 협약을 깼어.
Ragnar and King Horik broke
their agreement with him.
그걸 복수하러 오는거지.
He has returned to gain his revenge.
우린 어떻게 해야되죠?
What are we going to do?
뭘해야될거 같아?
(Panting) What do you
think we're going to do?
싸우러 간다.
We're going to fight.
이리와! 가자!
Aslaug: Come. Go! Go!
(Panicked chatter)
토르핀! 올라프! 안면씩 맡아.
Rollo: Torfin! Olaf!
One of you on each flank.
바리케이트 만드는걸 도와.
Help with the barricades.
라그나가 정예부대를 대려갔어.
Ragnar has taken all of
the best fighting men.
남은이들을 봐...
Look what we have left!
당신 뭐하는거야?
What are you doing?
뭐하는거 같아요?
What does it look like?
아니야 당신은 방패처녀가 아니라고.
Not you. You are not a shield-maiden.
- 당신은...
- 라그리타가 아니라구요?
- You're not...
- Lagertha?
시기 그레이트홀로 가줘.
Siggy, I need you to go
back to the great hall.
아스루그랑 그녀의 아이들을 찾아봐
Find Princess Aslaug and her children
그리고 산으로 도망가.
and take them up into the mountains.
- 그리구요?
- 기다려.
- And then what?
- Wait.
뭘기다려요?
For what?
신들이 우리를 위해 결정한일을.
For whatever the gods have
decided is about to happen.
이제 가!
Now go!
Man: 저리로 굴려!
Man: Roll them in there!
Woman: Fasten them on as quick as you can!
(Running footfalls)
(Barrels clatter)
(Water churns)
이쪽이 산으로 가는 길이예요.
Siggy: This way! To the mountains.
어서가 히비설크.
Hurry! Go, Hvitserk.
달려 빨리!
Aslaug: Run! Quickly!
(Oars splash through water)
돛을 내려라!
Sail down!
(Horn bellows)
저어! 저어!
Row! Row!
(Horn bellows)
단단히 붙어있어!
Rollo: Stay strong!
쉽게 오지 못하게해!
Don't make it easy for them!
불을 붙여라!
Light the fires!
(Water churns)
(Intimidating battle cries, clank shields)
(Pounding spears and axes)
(Intimidating shouts) Man: Archers!
- Warrior: Come on!
- (Pounding spears and axes)
(Pounding spears and axes)
노들어!
Oars!
자리를 지켜라
Rollo: Hold your places!
(Ships creak)
뛰어 내려라!
Jarl Borg: Jump ship!
(Loud battle cry, warrior splashes)
가랏!
Jarl Borg: Go!
(Battle cries, splashing)
(Arrows whoosh, striking)
(Attack cries, weapons clank)
Agghhhh! (Splash)
(Water splashing)
(Flames roar)
(Fighting grunts)
Aghhh! (Splash)
(Heavy blows, fighting grunts)
Agghhhh! (Splash)
(Fighting grunts, pained cries)
- Jarl bork: Ungh!
- Man: Aggghhhh!
Ungh! Oof! Agh!
빨리!
방패!
- Woman: As fast as you can!
- Girl: Shields!
(Fighting grunts, pained cries)
Aghhhh! Ungh!
(Flames roar)
(Fighting grunts, pained cries)
롤로!
Boy: Rollo!
(Fighting grunts)
(Axe blows, pained cries)
후퇴하라!
Rollo: Fall back!
♪
(Battle cry)
후퇴하라!
Fall back!
시장으로.
Back to the market place.
(Running footsteps)
빨리!
Move!
그래 도망가라 빨리 롤로 도망가!
Jarl Borg: (Shouting)
That's right, Rollo, run!
언제나 처럼 잘 도망가는군.
(Quietly) Run like you always do.
(Attack cries)
(Panicked screaming and shouting)
으아아!
Agghhhh!
Yah!
쏴!
Rollo: Loose!
(Arrows whoosh, striking)
으아아!
Agghhh!
쏴!
- (Arrows whoosh)
- Rollo: Loose!
쉴드월!!
- Jarl Borg: Shield-wall!
- (Arrows clatter)
(Quieting down)
- Boy: 이쪽이야.
- (Repositioning chatter)
- Boy: This way.
넌 이길수 없다 롤로!
Jarl Borg: You can't win, Rollo!
신이 자네를 살게할거라는데
Old warrior: There is no
disgrace in the eyes of the gods
의심이 없어 보이는군 롤로.
to save yourself for another day, Rollo.
(Arrows whoosh, striking)
(Pained cries)
자네의 첫번째 임무는 라그나의 자식들을
구하는거야.
Old warrior: Your first duty is
to try and save the sons of Ragnar.
항복해라!
Jarl Borg: Surrender!
가라 롤로!
Old warrior: Rollo, go!
내가 신에게 자네가 한일을 말할테니.
I will tell the gods what you have done.
(Running footsteps)
(Preparatory breaths)
이제 항복할텐가?
Jarl Borg: Now, do you surrender?
(Footsteps crunch in the dirt)
(Battle cry, axe slicing)
(Battle cries)
(Weapons clank, fighting grunts)
♪
(Footsteps crunch)
(Wind howls)
(Fire crackles)
(Footsteps scuff)
(Chuckles)
(Laughs victoriously)
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -